Tonight, we are going
Dnes večer uctíme
to worship the Lakshmi Principle within us.
princip Lakšmí uvnitř nás.
Lakshmi is the Goddess of wealth,
Lakšmí je bohyně blahobytu,
prosperity and also of health.
prosperity a také zdraví.
Actually your country is already blessed,
Vaše země je ve skutečnosti už požehnaná,
because you have so many things here.
protože zde máte tolik věcí.
Firstly, this country has got such a lot of petrol
Zaprvé tato země má takovou spoustu ropy,
and if discoveries are made there’s much more.
a budou-li další objevy, najdou jí mnohem víc.
Then secondly, you have got beautiful timber.
Zadruhé tu máte krásné stavební dřevo.
Then thirdly you’ve got lot of steel, very lot of steel, very good steel.
Zatřetí máte mnoho oceli, velmi mnoho oceli, velmi dobré oceli.
Also you have diamonds.
Též máte diamanty.
So many things you have, apart from that you have so much of heart.
Máte tolik věcí, a kromě toho máte tak velké srdce!
Also gold you have.
Také máte zlato.
So all these things are in abundance in this country.
Takže všechny tyto věci jsou v této zemi v nadbytku.
Only thing is you don’t yet have somebody who will manage
To jediné, co vám zatím chybí, je někdo, kdo zvládne,
to get to you people.
aby se to dostalo k vám, lidem.
I’m sure it will work out.
Jsem si jista, že se to podaří.
But in Sahaja Yoga,
V Sahadža józe však
we have to know that this Principle of Lakshmi,
musíme vědět, že nám tento Lakšmí princip
gives us a great sense of satisfaction.
dává velkou spokojenost.
If you don’t have satisfaction
Když nemáte spokojenost,
then any amount of Lakshmi cannot help you.
pak vám žádné množství Lakšmí nemůže pomoci.
One becomes very greedy.
Člověk se stane velmi lakomým.
You have something but you want to have more and more and more;
Něco máte, chcete však mít víc a víc.
and for that one adopts all kinds of methods and measures.
A člověk kvůli tomu přijme všechny možné metody a způsoby.
Thus you also have, a very bad Mafia system here,
A tak zde teď máte ten strašný systém mafie,
who are very greedy.
který je velmi hrabivý.
For Sahaja Yogis, one has to realize
Sahadžajogíni si musí uvědomit,
that he does not have to achieve anything – he’s already achieved.
že nemusí ničeho dosahovat, že už toho dosáhli.
First people try to seek food,
Nejprve se lidé snažili hledat něco k snědku,
in the Nabhi Chakra
v Nábhí čakře.
– then they eat – that is Swaha
Pak jedí, to je Svaha,
– then it is being retained in the body.
a potom je to uloženo v těle.
Now supposing somebody becomes very greedy of food,
Řekněme, že někdo začne velmi lačnit po jídle,
he gets sick, he has problems.
onemocní a bude mít problémy.
But he goes to the second stage
Jde však do dalšího stádia,
where he sustains it and called as Swadha,
vyživování, což se nazývá Svadha.
because he eats thinking that it is,
Jí, protože si myslí,
as a human being, his duty to eat, that’s all.
že jako lidská bytost má povinnost jíst, to je vše.
Not for taste, not for greed, not for showing off.
Ne pro chuť, ne pro nenasytnost, ne proto, aby se předváděl.
In a very simple manner he eats.
Jí velmi jednoduše.
Like in the west I have seen people are very particular about
Na Západě jsem viděla, že lidé velmi dbají na to,
where you put the spoon and where you put that.
kam položit lžíci a kam položit to a ono.
They spend thousands to buy those cutleries.
Utratí tisíce nakupováním těch příborů.
Now the thing that is the worst for the Lakshmi Principle is drinking.
Tím nejhorším pro Lakšmí je pití alkoholu.
It is alcohol.
Je to alkohol.
They say in India, that a bottle comes from one side
V Indii říkávají, že z jedné strany přichází láhev
and the Lakshmi runs away from another door.
a druhými dveřmi utíká pryč Lakšmí.
So Sahaja Yogis don’t need to drink.
Sahadžajogíní tedy nepotřebují pít alkohol.
They give up drinking,
Vzdávají se pití,
and thus Lakshmi Principle can be established much more easily.
takže Lakšmí princip se může upevnit mnohem snáz.
Now why should we have Lakshmi?
A nyní, proč bychom měli mít Lakšmí.
We should have Lakshmi
Lakšmí bychom měli mít z důvodu,
First of all the Lakshmi has got
Především, Lakšmí má v rukou
two beautiful pink colored lotuses in Her hand.
dva krásné, růžově zbarvené lotosy.
That symbolizes that a person who has money
To symbolizuje, že člověk, který má peníze,
should have a very comfortable house, which is very inviting
by měl mít velice pohodlný dům, který velmi láká, zve.
– pink color is for love and invitation.
Růžová barva je pro lásku a pozvání.
Now the beetle comes to the lotus
Pak přijde do lotosu brouk
and it has got all kinds of thorns on its body.
a má na těle mnoho různých ostnů.
The beetle comes to the lotus
Brouk přijde do lotosu,
to collect some honey
aby sesbíral nějaký med,
but it has got thorns on its body but the lotus accepts.
ale má na těle ostny; lotos to však akceptuje.
It invites, you see the lotus is very happy to have this beetle in it.
Lotos ho zve, je velmi šťastný, že má toho brouka uvnitř.
Now the beetle is seeking the honey
Brouk hledá med,
and it gets tired and sleeps inside the lotus
pak se unaví a usne uvnitř lotosu.
– so the lotus gives a beautiful corona – the bed for it to sleep
A lotos tomu broukovi poskytne krásnou korunku, lůžko k spánku
and all the fragrance of the lotus, for that beetle,
a všechnu svou vůni
till the morning.
až do rána.
Then when the beetle has rested well,
Potom, až si brouk dobře odpočine,
he gets his honey and then he flies out.
dostane svůj med a odletí pryč.
We can state poetically
Poeticky to můžeme vyjádřit tak,
that the beetle is respected by the lotus
že lotos brouka respektuje,
because it is seeking the honey.
protože brouk hledá med.
Even if it has got thorns, doesn’t matter.
Přestože má ostny, nevadí to.
Thus you people who have been seeking the truth,
Tak jako vy lidé, kteří hledáte pravdu,
have received it on your Sahasrara, which is just like a lotus.
jste ji obdrželi ve své Sahasráře, která je také jako lotos.
Whatever you have done, whatever was the past is not important,
Ať už jste udělali cokoli, měli jakoukoli minulost, to není důležité.
you get your dignity because you are seeking the truth.
Získáte svou důstojnost, protože hledáte pravdu.
Also when people get saturated with Lakshmi,
Také když jsou lidé přesyceni Lakšmí,
as in the West I have seen,
jak jsem to viděla na Západě,
they take to seeking – they get fed up,
začnou hledat. Začnou být znechucení,
because material things is not Lakshmi,
protože materiální věci nejsou Lakšmí.
because it doesn’t give any satisfaction.
Nedávají žádnou spokojenost.
So the other thing that Lakshmi has in Her hand
Takže další věcí, kterou Lakšmí dělá, je,
- what happens that She puts one hand like this -
že dává ruku takto.
this hand suggests that a person who has money
A ta ruka naznačuje, že osoba, která má peníze,
has to give and share – not to take it for oneself.
musí dávat a dělit se. Ne si je nechávat pro sebe.
If they do not share,
Pokud se lidé nedělí,
then they cannot enjoy the Principle of Lakshmi
nemohou se těšit principem Lakšmí,
when giving to others is so joyful.
kdy dávání ostatním je tak radostné!
Another hand is like this -
Druhá ruka je takto.
this hand of the Goddess, suggests that those who are
Tato ruka Bohyně naznačuje, že těm, kteří jsou
under your care, your relations, your friends,
pod vaší ochranou, vašim příbuzným, vašim přátelům,
all those people, must be given complete protection by you.
všem těmto lidem musíte plně poskytnout svoji ochranu.
Anything happens in your family,
Ať už se ve vaší rodině stane cokoli,
anything happens to your relations or to your friends,
nebo když se něco stane vašim příbuzným či přátelům,
you must stand by that person.
musíte stát při nich.
Some people try to help their relations
Někteří lidé se snaží pomoci svým příbuzným,
by say – many politicians do that way - by cheating.
řekněme, tak jak to dělá mnoho politiků - podváděním.
But by cheating, what you are doing
Když však podvádíte,
is you are spoiling the life of that relation,
kazíte tomu příbuznému život.
So he’ll be losing his name, his dignity, everything -
On pak ztratí své jméno, důstojnost, všechno,
specially his moral character.
zvláště pak svůj morální charakter.
So with the Lakshmi, you must have your morality intact.
Mít Lakšmí princip tedy znamená, že vaše morálka musí být bez úhony.
In a country, like now, say America and all such people,
V zemi, jako je dnes například Amerika a všechny podobné,
there are horrible films coming
vznikají hrozné filmy
and people are taking to the science, we call it, alakshmi.
a lidé se uchylují k vědě. Říkáme tomu a-Lakšmí.
A person who has Lakshmi should dress up in a decent manner -
Člověk, který má Lakšmí, by se měl oblékat patřičným způsobem,
women and men.
jak ženy, tak muži.
I find on the street women walking with very short clothes.
Vidím, že po ulici chodí ženy ve velmi krátkých šatech.
With that, what will happen your Nabhi chakra will be caught,
Takto bude vaše Nábhí čakra napadena
and you will have problems with money.
a budete mít problémy s penězi.
So the wealth that you have
Bohatství, které máte,
should be seen in your temperament, in your nature,
by tedy mělo být vidět ve vašem temperamentu, ve vaší povaze,
in your behavior, in your living.
ve vašem chování, v tom, jak žijete.
Moreover the person who has Lakshmi has to be a very humble man.
A navíc člověk, který má Lakšmí, musí být velmi pokorný.
For example, Shri Lakshmi is standing on a lotus.
Kupříkladu, Šrí Lakšmí stojí na lotosu.
Lotus is the lightest flower you could think
Lotos je nejlehčí květina,
because it floats over the water.
protože plave na vodní hladině.
So Her temperament should be not of a very serious type
Takže Její povaha by neměla být příliš vážná,
but of a very mirthful...
ale velmi radostná.
and She doesn’t show off
Ona se nepředvádí,
because it’s such a simple thing, like a lotus, to stand on that.
protože stát na lotosu je tak prostá věc.
So for people who have money, or who have wealth
Takže lidé, kteří mají peníze nebo bohatství,
should not try to show off by very big cars and this and that.
by se neměli pokoušet předvádět velkými auty a podobně.
That of course does not mean that you should become sanyasis.
To ovšem neznamená, že byste se měli stát sanjásíny.
On the contrary, you should be very well dignified personalities.
Naopak, měli byste být velmi důstojnými osobnostmi.
But there should be detachment.
Měla by zde však být odpoutanost.
As you saw Raja Janaka, He was a king
Jak jste viděli, Rádža Džanaka byl králem,
and still He was so detached,
a přesto byl tak odpoutaný,
that all the Saints used to go and touch the feet of Raja Janaka.
že se všichni světci přicházeli dotknout Jeho chodidel.
So there was this fellow called Nachiketa, he asked his master
Existoval člověk jménem Načiketa, který se zeptal svého mistra:
“Why do you touch His feet? - He is a king”.
„Proč se dotýkáš Jeho chodidel? On je král.“
So the master said “All right – you go and meet Him now”.
Mistr řekl: „Dobrá, jdi se s ním teď setkat.“
So what he saw was that Janaka had all the luxuries of life.
A Načiketa viděl, že Džanaka měl veškerý luxus života.
He was living in the palace
Žil v paláci
and in the procession there were thousands and thousands of people
a při procesí na něj tisíce lidí
who were throwing pearls on him.
házelo perly.
So Nachiketa thought he should get one pearl at least.
Načiketa si pomyslel, že by alespoň jednu perlu chtěl získat.
Next day, he went to Raja Janaka
Druhý den šel k Rádžovi Džanakovi
and asked Him, “Give me Self-realization.”
a požádal Ho: „Dejte mi seberealizaci.“
So Raja Janaka said, “I can give you all My kingdom
Rádža Džanaka řekl: „Můžu ti dát celé své království,
but not Self-realization, very difficult,
ale ne seberealizaci, to je velmi těžké,
because you are possessed by the idea of money,
protože jsi posedlý představou peněz.
such a person cannot get Realization."
A taková osoba nemůže dostat realizaci.“
He said, “All right, I will live here till I get Realization.
Načiketa řekl: „Dobrá, budu zde žít, dokud nedostanu realizaci.“
Next day Raja Janaka took him for a bath in the river
Druhý den ho Rádža Džanaka vzal s sebou vykoupat se v řece
and He was enjoying the bath.
a užíval si koupání.
And people came and told Him that there is a fire in His palace.
Přišli k němu lidé a řekli, že v jeho paláci hoří.
But Raja Janaka was meditating,
Rádža Džanaka však meditoval,
He didn’t bother.
nenechal se rušit.
Then they said that the people who are in the palace have run away.
Pak mu řekli, že lidé, kteří byli v paláci, utekli pryč.
Then he says that, somebody said
Pak někdo řekl,
that now the fire is coming here.
že nyní se ten oheň blíží k nim.
Still Raja Janaka was meditating.
Rádža Džanaka stále meditoval.
But Nachiketa ran out
Načiketa však vyběhnul z vody,
because his clothes were outside, so ran out to save his….
protože jeho věci byly venku a on je utíkal zachránit.
And still Raja Janaka was not bothered.
Rádža Džanaka se však ani tehdy nenechal vyrušit.
So when He came out He told him, "Nachiketa, this is all Mahamaya."
Když vyšel z vody ven, řekl: „Načiketo, toto všechno je Mahámája.“
This is how you are tested,
Takto jsi testován.
if you are money-oriented you cannot get Self-realization.
Pokud jsi orientován na peníze, nemůžeš získat seberealizaci.
She’s the one who is testing.
Ona je Tou, která testuje.
All the greedy people,
Všichni nenasytní lidé,
all the people, for money’s sake, do all kinds of thing,
všichni lidé, kteří pro peníze dělají všechny možné věci,
as you have here, Mafias, - will be all punished.
tak jako zde máte mafii, ti všichni budou potrestáni.
In any case they are not happy people, satisfied people,
V žádném případě to nejsou šťastní, spokojení lidé,
they are all the time worried.
neustále si dělají starosti.
So first thing you must have is satisfaction.
Takže první věc, kterou musíte mít, je spokojenost.
This is a very important thing in modern times to understand.
Toto je velmi důležitá věc, kterou je v moderní době třeba pochopit.
Because is said also in the economics,
I v ekonomice se říká,
that wants are not satiable in general.
že potřeby nejsou všeobecně uspokojitelné.
You want today a carpet – all right, have it.
Dnes chcete koberec, dobrá, mějte ho.
You work very hard, save money to buy a carpet,
Pracujete velmi tvrdě, šetříte peníze, abyste si koupili koberec.
then you have the carpet, you want to have a house –
Potom máte koberec, ale chcete mít dům.
you never enjoy the carpet,
Nikdy nemáte radost z koberce,
for which you have worked so hard.
kvůli kterému jste tak tvrdě pracovali.
Then you have a house,
Pak máte dům,
so when you get the house, you want to have a car –
a když máte dům, tak chcete mít auto.
then from car, you want, I think, helicopter, maybe an aeroplane.
A po autě chcete, myslím, helikoptéru, možná letadlo.
This is how it goes on
Takovým způsobem to pokračuje
and you work so hard and have no satisfaction.
a vy tak tvrdě pracujete a nemáte žádnou spokojenost.
Because of this, in these modern times, people are extremely restless.
Kvůli tomu jsou lidé v této moderní době extrémně neklidní.
There is no peace in your heart
Ve vašem srdci není žádný mír.
but if you have this Lakshmi Principle in you,
Když však v sobě máte tento Lakšmí princip,
you will feel extremely satisfied
budete se cítit neobyčejně spokojení
with everything that is materialistic.
se vším, co je materiální.
If you have, well and good, if you don’t have, well and good.
Pokud máte, velmi dobře, pokud ne, také velmi dobře,
But after that, this Mahalakshmi Principle is awakened within you,
protože potom se ve vás tento Mahálakšmí princip probouzí,
that you start seeking.
tím že začnete hledat.
And then that is also, later on as you have seen, is granted,
A to je vám pak, jak jste viděli, později, také dáno,
because you get your Self-realization.
protože získáte svou seberealizaci.
So nothing to copy these horrible materialistic people,
Není tedy proč napodobovat ty hrozné, materialistické lidi.
but we have to be satisfied with what we have
Musíme však být spokojeni s tím, co máme,
and we should express our love by giving something,
a měli bychom vyjadřovat svou lásku dáváním něčeho,
whatever it is, to the needy person.
čehokoli, osobě, která má nouzi.
I have seen Myself,
Co se týče Mě samotné,
I find it very difficult to buy anything for Myself.
pro Mě je těžké koupit si něco pro sebe.
If it is expensive, I think I should not buy it.
Pokud je to drahé, říkám si, že bych si to neměla kupovat.
So once I went to a shop, I wanted to buy a particular sari,
Jednou jsem šla do obchodu, chtěla jsem si koupit jedno sárí,
but I thought it was too expensive – I didn’t buy it.
ale protože jsem si myslela, že je příliš drahé, nekoupila jsem ho.
But one Sahaja Yogi was with Me – he went and bought it
Byl tam se ale Mnou jeden sahadžajogín, který šel, koupil ho
and gave it to Me on My birthday
a dal Mi ho k narozeninám
and I just started crying, you know, it’s too much.
a Já jsem se prostě rozplakala. Víte, bylo to příliš.
We have stories like this in our Ramayana also,
Podobné příběhy máme i v naší Rámajáně,
where Shri Rama ate the sour ber.
kdy Šrí Ráma snědl kyselé plody - bobule.
We call it ber, I don't know - you too call it ber - must be a story like that.
My tomu říkáme „bér“, nevím, vy tomu taky říkáte „bér“,
She told Shri Ram that,
Jedna žena řekla Šrí Rámovi
- she was an old woman from a down-trodden society -
- byla to stará žena z nižších vrstev společnosti:
that “I have eaten every, I have touched every ber with my teeth,
„Ochutnala jsem všechny, všech jsem se dotkla svými zuby,
you see, and I have found out that none of them are sour.”
víte, a zjistila jsem, že žádná není kyselá.“
In India, nobody eats anything which is touched by mouth,
V Indii nikdo nejí nic, čeho se někdo dotkl ústy.
on any food, is regarded utishta,  is something wrong.
Jakékoli takové jídlo se považuje za „utišta“, za něco špatného.
But Shri Rama immediately took,
Šrí Ráma si však hned vzal
He said, “Oh, how sweet of you to have done this tasting for Me.”
a řekl: „Ach, jak milé, že jsi to kvůli Mně ochutnala.“
But His brother was very angry, he didn’t like it, Lakshmana.
Jeho bratr Lakšman se však rozzlobil, nelíbilo se mu to.
Shri Rama ate, He said, “I have never eaten such beautiful bers.”
Šrí Ráma jedl a řekl: „Nikdy jsem nejedl tak výborné bobule.“
So His wife Sita said,
A tak Jeho žena Síta řekla:
“Give Me also, little bit, I am your half thing you should give me.”
„Dej Mi také trošku, jsem Tvá „polovina“, měl bys Mi dát.“
So when Shri Rama gave Her, She ate and She said,
Když Jí Šrí Ráma dal, snědla je a řekla:
“Oh my goodness what a beautiful fruit this one is.”
„Svatá dobroto, jaké skvělé ovoce!“
So Lakshmana said, “Why not give Me?”
Lakšmana tedy řekl: „Proč nedostanu také?“
He asked His sister-in-law,
Požádal svou švagrovou:
“Give me also”, She said “No, because you were so angry.”
„Dej mi taky.“ Ona však řekla: „Nedám, protože ses tak hněval.“
But She gave it to Lakshmana, and Lakshmana said,
Pak ale Lakšmanovi dala a on řekl:
“I have never eaten such beautiful fruits.”
„Nikdy jsem nejedl tak výborné ovoce.“
What was in that ber was nothing
U těch bobulí šlo v podstatě jen o to
but giving sense of this old lady.
vyjádřit touhu té staré paní dávat.
She didn’t have anything to give – she was a poor lady –
Ona neměla co dát, byla to chudá žena
so she did all this just to give to Shri Rama.
a udělala všechno pro to, aby je dala Šrí Rámovi.
So the sharing of your things is an extremely joy-giving thing.
Takže dělit se o své věci dává extrémní radost.
The other day we had brought some presents,
Jindy jsme přivezli nějaké dárky,
I mean nothing so great, but you all so enjoyed it, and I too enjoyed it.
myslím, že to nebylo nic velkého,
That is how we all have to live,
Takovým způsobem musíme žít my všichni.
that is how all of us have to live together - sharing things.
Takto my všichni musíme žít spolu, o vše se dělit.
Don’t think about yourself, think of others.
Nemyslete na sebe, myslete na ostatní.
Think what others like.
Myslete na to, co mají rádi druzí.
In India, the Gruha Lakshmis are that way very good.
V Indii jsou Gruha Lakšmí po této stránce velmi dobré.
They know what you like to eat.
Ony vědí, co rádi jíte.
So if you go to their house,
Takže když jdete do jejich domu,
immediately they will ask, "Please come for dinner."
ihned požádají: „Prosím, přijď na večeři.“
And they will make what I would like
A uvaří to, co bych si ráda dala,
and I would love to eat. They’ll go out of the way to make that.
co bych ráda jedla. Udělají pro to první a poslední.
But not only for Me, for anyone.
Ale nejen pro Mě, pro kohokoli.
It’s such a joy-giving thing to cook for others.
Vařit pro druhé dává takovou radost!
So the principle of Lakshmi is only enjoyed
Takže z principu Lakšmí je možné se těšit,
when you share it with others.
když to sdílíte s ostatními.
My father was a great Realized soul,
Můj otec byl velká realizovaná duše
and he never used to close the doors or windows in the night.
a nikdy nezavíral na noc okna ani dveře.
And one day a thief came and took away the gramophone that he had.
A jednoho dne přišel zloděj a odnesl gramofon, který patřil otci.
So he felt very sad that he has taken away the gramophone now,
Otec byl velmi smutný, že ten zloděj odnesl gramofon:
what about records – he can’t buy –
„No a co gramofonové desky? On si je nemůže koupit,
how will he play?
co si bude přehrávat?“
So My mother joked that, better give it in the newspaper that,
Matka si dělala legraci, že by se mělo dát do novin:
“to the thief who has taken away our gramophone,
„Zloději, který odnesl náš gramofon -
please come and take away the records also.”
přijďte prosím a odneste si i gramofonové desky.“
This is a sign of Lakshmi Principle.
Toto je projev principu Lakšmí.
The one who is satisfied
Ten, kdo je spokojený,
and is happiest when he can give something.
je nejšťastnější, když může něco dát.
If you give with one hand you’ll get from ten hands.
Když dáte jednou rukou, dostanete z deseti dalších.
So we have to learn to share,
Takže se musíme naučit dělit se.
as it is you are giving the highest thing to others -
Vždyť dáváte ostatním tu nejvyšší věc,
that is Self-realization.
kterou je seberealizace.
What more can you give?
Co víc můžete dát?
You must have seen when you give Self-realization,
Určitě jste si všimli, že když dáváte seberealizaci,
how happy you feel.
cítíte se šťastní.
The greatest happiness and the greatest joy
Největší štěstí a největší radost
is in giving Realizations to others.
je dávání realizací druhým.
I have seen people, their faces change
Viděla jsem, jak se lidem mění obličej.
and people who give Realization, their faces also get full of light.
A obličeje lidí, kteří dávají realizaci, jsou také plné světla.
We are a new society, we are people of new age,
Jsme nová společnost, jsme lidé nového věku,
where we have got our satisfaction in higher things.
kdy naše spokojenost přichází z vyšších věcí.
There are many Sahaja Yogis who have been working,
Je tu mnoho sahadžajogínů, kteří pracují
giving Realization, but there are many who do not.
a dávají realizace, ale je mnoho těch, kteří je nedávají.
Unless and until you share your joy with others,
Dokud se o svou radost nebudete dělit s ostatními,
you will not be happy.
nebudete šťastní.
I heard the other day,
Onehdy
one lady told Me that her father, mother are against Sahaja Yoga.
Mi jedna paní řekla, že její otec a matka jsou proti Sahadža józe.
I said, “What is your relationship?”
Zeptala jsem se jí: „Jaký je tvůj vztah k nim?“
She said, “I don’t talk to them, I don’t like them,
Řekla Mi: „Nemluvím s nimi, nemám je ráda
the way they are against Sahaja Yoga”.
za to, že jsou proti Sahadža józe.“
I told her, “You change your attitude,
Řekla jsem jí: „Změň svůj postoj,
take some flowers for them, some present for them,
vezmi jim nějaké květiny, nějaký dárek,
talk to them in a very sweet manner.
mluv s nimi velmi sladce.
Because you have become such a dry person,
Nemají rádi Sahadža jógu,
that’s why they don’t like Sahaja Yoga."
protože se z tebe stala strašně suchá osoba.“
And it worked, it worked, the parents are now in Sahaja Yoga.
A fungovalo to, pracovalo to a její rodiče jsou nyní v Sahadža józe.
So the attitude of a Sahaja Yogi
Takže postoj sahadžajogína
towards a non-Sahaja Yogi should be of helping,
k nesahadžajogínovi by měl být o pomáhání,
of supporting, of sharing.
podporování a dělení se.
But I must warn you there are some Sahaja Yogis
Musím vás ale varovat. Existují sahadžajogíni,
who will try to have their own party.
kteří se pokusí mít svou vlastní skupinu.
They are very power-oriented.
Jsou velmi orientovaní na moc.
They will have an exclusive party.
Budou mít svoji výlučnou skupinu.
It is a dangerous sign – it’s a cancer.
To je nebezpečný úkaz - to je rakovina.
Everything should be collective.
Všechno by mělo být kolektivní.
Anybody who does that kind of thing,
Měli byste vědět, že ten,
you should know is a possessed person,
kdo dělá takové věci, je posedlý.
and you will be harmed if you follow such a person.
A budete-li takového člověka následovat, ublíží vám to.
We are all collective, we have to know everything among each other
Všichni jsme kolektivní, musíme o sobě navzájem vědět všechno
and we have to live like one family,
a musíme žít jako jedna rodina.
not only in Russia but all over the world.
Nejen v Rusku, ale na celém světě.
Once you develop that kind of a love for everyone,
Jakmile si rozvinete tento druh lásky pro každého,
then you will be surprised you have become a great personality.
budete překvapeni, že jste se stali velkou osobností.
That means a drop becomes the ocean.
To znamená, že kapka se stává oceánem.
I can go on saying about Lakshmi Principle for hours together.
O Lakšmí principu mohu mluvit celé hodiny.
There are nine Lakshmis,
Existuje devět Lakšmí,
but next time I’ll tell you.
ale to vám povím příště.
One of them is Gruha Lakshmi, is the housewife,
Jedna z nich je Gruha Lakšmí, to je hospodyně,
and another is the Raja Lakshmi, which is the power of a king
a další je Rádža Lakšmí, která je silou krále
or of a person who is administrator or who is a bureaucrat.
nebo člověka, který je správcem nebo nějakým funkcionářem.
But I would request you
Chtěla bych vás požádat,
to understand that you have got the greatest treasure
abyste pochopili, že jste dostali to největší bohatství,
that very few people have got in this world.
které získalo jen velmi málo lidí na světě.
Nourish it with your love.
Vyživte ho svou láskou.
Nourish it with your compassion and peaceful existence.
Dejte mu výživu svým milosrdenstvím a míruplnou existencí.
If there is any problem, anything
Pokud náhle vyvstane nějaký problém, cokoli,
– suddenly, you must become peaceful within.
musíte se zklidnit uvnitř.
Then immediately you’ll find solution will come before you.
Pak ihned najdete řešení, přijde k vám.
This is the subtle of Lakshmi Principle.
Toto je subtilnost Lakšmí principu.
I hope all of you will develop it and enjoy it.
Doufám, že si ho všichni rozvinete a budete se jím těšit.
Before I come next year, I will see that you all have,
Doufám, že než příští rok přijedu, uvidím, že jste všichni,
each person, has given Realization at least to hundred people.
každý z vás, dali realizaci alespoň sto lidem.
You got powers,
Dostali jste síly,
you’ve got powers, you have knowledge, don’t waste it,
dostali jste síly, máte vědění, nepromarněte to!
we have to save the world.
Musíme zachránit svět.
So, May God Bless you all.
Nuže, kéž vám všem Bůh žehná.